Guide to the Western Connecticut State University Photographs and Miscellanea RG 8
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series III: Clippings, 55202
  - 2007 - Present, 55696
    - Digest (8 issues), Jan 2009 - Dec 2009; 55700 (Box Clippings Digest 6, Item 63-70)
      June 2009 Digest: Apr 23: Stephen Price and Wendy Youngblood awarded Fulbright Scholarships; Apr 23: Earth Day 2009, Students dig into Roots & Shoots; May 10: WestConn hosts Research Day; May 17: Film fest returns bigger than ever; May 17: "The Muses" presented by WCSU's music department; May 17: Newsweek columnist Jonathan Alter and Michael P. Meotti, Commissioner of Connecticut's Department of Higher Education, to speak at WestConn's Commencement; May 21: Roberts Avenue School closes; May 29-Jun 1: CT Film Festival; Jun 8: Watermilfoil research grows at Candlewood Lake.
      July 2009 Digest: May 31: WestConn Professor Pinou take scientific "Initiative;" May 31: WestConn's University Ball; Jun 28: Operation Care Package at WCSU; Jun 28: WestConn prepares for its new arts center; Jun 24,29: Did drawdown foil the watermilfoil? Jul 5,9: Summer at Ives Concert Park; Jul 20: Author Frank McCourt dies; Jul 19: New Connecticut Science Center in Hartford.
      October 2009 Digest: Jul 9: Ives thrives; Jul 12: G.I. Bill changes causing confusion; Jul 20: Frank McCourt "a neighbor" in Litchfield County; Jul 31: WestConn's production of "The Tempest: A Musical Enchantment" at Ives Concert Park; Aug 2,6: Readings at WestConn by author Daniel Asa Rose; Aug 14: Abigail Disney, filmmaker and philanthropist, to speak at WestConn; Aug 19: WCSU's The Tempest at Edinburgh '09; Aug 19: Danbury's new "Ellsworth Avenue Elementary School; Aug 25, Sep 16, Oct 4: One Book, One Community book on teenage mental illness; Aug 29: WestConn welcomes its biggest class; Sep-Oct 09: View from out here by Christopher L. Kukk, The advantages of teaching overseas with a family; Sep 4; WCSU to receive 2009 award from the Housatonic Valley Cultural Alliance; Sep 6: Dr. Mel Goldstein's new book "Dr. Mel's Connecticut Climate Book;" Sep 11,23: Swine flu case probable; Sep 22: WestConn's EllenDurnin says women need to negotiate more; Sep 30: Business Women's Forum focuses on survival; Oct 3: WestConn forum to focus on racism and division; Oct 4: WestConn builds upon a legacy of culture and opportunity.
      Sports: Sep 4: Women's soccer.
      Dec 2009 Digest: Oct 4: Swin flu virus; Nov 6: WestConn takes on violence against women; Nov 6: Truth and consequences of the CUS; Sep 12: Mary Edgett 107th birthday; Nov 12: WestConn honors veterans; Nov 13: WCSU's Debate Team to debate nuclear weapons; Nov 14: Morganti endows WestConn scholarship; Nov 17: Candlewood Lake owners plan shoow winter drawdown; Nov 24: WestConn speaker Juan Melendez, released after 17 years on death row.
      Sports: Nov 12: WestConn athletes named to All-Little East Conference teams; Nov 21:WestConn running back Tyler DeRosa honored; Nov 29: Colonials win WestConnn Classic; Dec.26: Men's basketball; Katie Moffo returns to lead Colonials on court.
    - Digest (8 issues), Feb 2010 - Dec 2010; 55701 (Box Clippings Digest 6, Item 71-78)
      Includes Feb, Apr-Jul, Sep, Oct and Dec.
      February 2010 Digest: Dec 5: Prof and author Kevin Gutzman's bestselling book "The Politically Incorrect Guide to the Constitution;" Dec 11: WestConn tuition hike; Dec 11: James Schmotter interview on respect for colleges; Dec 13: "Meet the Bag Lady of Ridgefield High School" by Darla Shaw; Dec 13: Dr. Christopher Kukk lectures his nuclear proliferation class; Dec 16: 2009 Retrospective, Weathering the Economic Storm; Dec 26: WestConn student promotes dental hygiene in Africa; Jan 8: Danbury's past unearthed in Brooklyn archives; Jan 17: WestConn adds Financial Literacy Institute funded by the university and Union Savings Bank; Jan 19: Local civil rights leaders assess progress.
      Sports: Jan 6: WestConn's Melissa Teel named MVP of the Naismith Classic Tournament.
      April 2010 Digest: Feb 7: Prof Jean Hatcherson interview; Feb 19: Vets find new battle in G.I. Bill; Feb 26, Mar 3: "A Fle in Her Ear" production by WestConn's Theatre Arts Department; Feb 27: Women's history and culture series at WestConn; Mar 2: How to save humanity from nature's whims by Alex Standish, Prof of Geography; Mar 12: Women's History Month.
      Sports: Feb 11: WestConn names three new men's lacross assistants; Feb 19: WestConn's DaQuan Brooks named ECAC New England player of the week; Feb 21: Secniors Francesca Testa and Katie Meleg lead WestConn swimmers at New Englands; Feb 21: Men's and women's basketball.
      May 2010 Digest: Apr 7: Mary Edgett dies at 107; Apr 9: Eight professors honored for outstanding teaching research; Apr 12: Retired Prof Phillip K. Lu interview; Apr 14: WestConn gives college experience to area kids with special needs; Apr 22: Burton Peretti appears on "Who Do You Think You Are" with Susan Sarandon; Apr 22: Earth Day showcases Jim Dyer; Apr 25: Social media is an emerging career field; Apr 25: Ives Concert Park breaks ground on a new garden at its entrace; Apr 29: Culture Fair organized by IMPACT, a student organization at WCSU; Apr 29: WestConn Prof Eric Lewis to debut newly finished Mozart work; May 9: Dr. Story Musgrave interview.
      Sports: May 7: Brittany Connors pitches Colonials into Little East quarterfinals.
      June 2010 Digest: May 21: WestConn adds doctoral degree to university's nursing program; May 23: State colleges grow in stature; May 28: $45,000 grant will help Lake Kenosia's problems; Jun 1: Hord Foundation awards scholarships; Jun 6: One Book, One Community chooses Vietname War Book.
      July 2010 Digest: Jun 9: WestConn to offer Portugese and Chinese language classes for the first time; Jun 20: WestConn students publish paper on Staples growth; Jun 22: Brookfield Resident Wins WestConn's 2010 Provost Prize for Biology Project WEB FIRST; Jun 22: Three WestConn deans, Ellen Durnin, Linda Vaden-Goad, and Lynne Clark, to move on to jobs at other schools; Jul 5,8: Candlewood Lake: WestConn students study use of weevils to control invasive plant; Jul 8: Ted Hines remembered; Jul 9: WestConn will rent textbooks; Jul 15: Student Mercedes DeMasi elected to CSUS Board of Trustees.
      September 2010 Digest: Jul 28: Prof Chris Kukk and China's water problems; Aug 2: Joe DiGuiseppi transforms bare wall into art; Aug 5: Danbury Armory may change hands; Aug 17: WCSU White Street signs to unify campus; Aug 17: Prof Erik Tonner's "The Reluctant Detective" film shoots in Danbury; Aug 28: WestConn welcomes the class of 2014; Aug 28: One Book, One Community, author Tim O'Brien shares his Vietnam experience; Aug 29: The road to the Hat City; Sep 5: Danbury celebrates 325th birthday; Sep 6: WXCI seeks listeners' input; Sep 5: WestConn professor Karen Daley discusses nursing doctorate; Sep 14: Candlewood Authority starts watermilfoil initiative; Sep 15: Connecticut biologist Dr. Leslie Mehrhoff will discuss spread of invasive plants; Sep 15: Dr. Christopher Kukk speaks about China's efforts to balance its drive for economic growth with new emphasis on environmental protection.
      October 2010 Digest: Sep 18: Jane Goodall to train people in environmental education; Prof Kevin Gutzman speaks about the Constitution; Sep 25: Leslie Mehrhoff interview on invasive plants; Sep 30, Oct 8: "As Bees in Honey Drown" production; Oct 1: Candlewood Lake Authority's new initiative regarding Watermilfoil; Oct 8: Danbury filmmakers make documentary on Still River; Oct 10,18: Jane Goodall lecture about her research on champanzees and how humans need to clean up their act to protect the rest of life on Earth; Oct 10: WestConn adds musical theatre degree; Oct 13,15: Pulitizer Prize finalist Tim O'Brien to visit Danbury.
      Sports: Sep 1: Women's basketball.
      December 2010: Oct 2: Chris Kukk profile; Oct 22: Bring back Danbury's ghost tours (Darla Shaw); Oct 22,29: Author Tim O'Brien's speaks about his book "The things I carried;" Nov 2: "The Best Little Whorehouse in Texas" production by the Theatre Arts Department; Nov 21: New Fairfield: Study to look at effect on watermilfoil in Candlewood Lake; Dec 5: A lesson in social media; Dec 6: Undocumented students step out of shadows.
    - Digest (6 issues), Feb 2011 - Dec 2011; 55702 (Box Clippings Digest 7, Item 79-84)
      Includes Feb, Apr, May, Sep, Oct, and Dec.
      February 2011 Digest: Dec 5: A lesson in social media; Dec 15: WestConn among state universities with record transfer students; Dec 26: Mary Kiniry, advocate for teens; Jan 2: Bass player Kevin Smith with "Saturday Night Live;" Jan 19,20: Remembering JFK; Jan 21: WestConn student Conor Daniel Bartram's play "Credence" debuts this weekend; Jan 29: Lake study calls for more study; Jan 31: The Case for Chaos (Prof John Briggs); Feb 4: Remembering Ella Grasso.
      Sports: Dec. 13: Melissa Teel named Little East Conference basketball Player of the week.
      April 2011 Digest: Feb 23,24,25: Prof Abubaker Saad explains crisis in Libya; Mar 1,4: Chekhov Classic "Three Sisters" production by the Theatre Arts Department; Mar 2: Students, faculty praise WestConn; Mar 2,9: Prof Abubaker Saad interview; Mar 15: "Malloy plan weakens state universities' autonomy" by John Briggs in the Hartford Courant; Mar 22: WestConn Opera presents "Street Scene" by Kurt Weill; Mar 23-25: Dr. Mell will speak at WestConn; Mar 29: Panel looks to stop spread of zebra mussels; Mar 30-31: State oks $80M performance center.
      Sports: Mar 4: Men and women's basketball.
      May 2011 Digest: Apr 3: Dr. Mel and Arlene Goldstein, how they met; Apr 3: WestConn Siociety Luncheon; Apr 5: Two WestConn seniors, Emily Cole and Bryan Bielefeldt, earn Bernard Awards; Apr 8: Dr. Mel Goldstein: "I Love Hurricanes;" Apr 15: Helen Prejean, author of Dead Man Walking, speaks against death penality; Apr 18: Paul Steinmetz named interim vice presdident for institutional advancement at WCSU; May 3: Bin Laden news met with tempered jubilation; May 8: WXCI hosts Zombie Walk.
      September 2011 Digest: Jul 23: Researchers in search of zebra mussels; Jul 28: WestConn's Carol Hawkes proves inspirational; Aug 8,10: One Book, One Community selection "Farewell, My Subaru" by Doug Fine; Aug 21: Photronics awards scholarships to 34 college students; Aug 23: WestConn professor Abubaker Saad watching Gadhafi's fall; Aug 24,25: Dr. Mel Retires, cites health; Aug 27: Dr. Mel says Irene may be our hurricane; Sep 5: Dr. Mel eases into retirement; Sep 10: Gregg Taylor recalls 9/11; Sep 13: Local chapter of The Links welcomes WestConn's African-American provost.
      October 2011 Digest: Sep 14: Rare marbled salamander discovered in Danbury; Sep 21: Three dilapidated apartment houses to be demolished; Sep 21: A green will replace Roberts Avenue School; Sep 26: Pianist Peter Frankl to perform at WCSU; Sep 27: Danbury Museum & Historical Society; Sep 27: Saving the city's historical places; Oct 4,19-20: State Supreme Court justices to hear cases at WCSU; Oct 5: WCSU keeps eye on campus crosswalks; Oct 16: Parents of Brookfield High students complain about "The Bluest Eye" by Toni Morrison; Oct 17: Danbury NAACP honors George Coleman; Oct 17-18: WestConn to break ground on visual arts building; Oct 20: In the forecast: A touching special on "Dr. Mel" Saturday; Oct 20-21,24: Reactions locally and globally to Gaddafi's death.
      December 2011 Digest: Oct 23: Danbury's environmental history; Oct 24: Doug Fine interview; Oct 25,28: "Sweeney Todd" production by WCSU's Theatre Arts Department; Oct 26: Abubaker Saad, former Gadhafi interpreter, remembers Libyan tyrant; Nov 28: Storm highlights need for emergency home health care planning; Nov 9: WCSU students to cover elections; Nov 10,13: WestConn salute to vets; Nov 20: Steel Magnolias, David Boyajian interview; Nov 21: WestConn provost among top 100 influential blacks in state; Nov 22: WCSU jazz concert to feature John Patitucci; Nov 29: White Street task force to take on dangerous Danbury crossing.
    - Digest (1 issue), Jan 2012; 55703 (Box Clippings Digest 7, Item 85)
      Includes Jan.
      January 2012 Digest: Dec: A Christmas Carol at WCSU; Dec 7: WestConn student Dong Lin remembered at vigil; Dec 9,26: Two students, Alex Tettey, Jr. and Michael Fraser, elected to Board of Regents for Higher Education; Dec 13: "Sweeney Todd" chosen to be part of the Kennedy Center American College Theatre Festival in Fitchubrg, Mass; Dec 15: WCSU to present Holiday Jazz and "A Baby Boomer Christmas;" Dec 16: A zebra mussel year; Dec 21: Danbury makes list of artistic cities; Jan 13: Prof Mullaney meets with Sinn Fein leader; Jan 17-18: Dalai Lama to speak in Connecticut in October; Jan 18: James Schmotter appointed chairman of the NCAA Division III Presidents Council' Jan 18: Tibetan Prime Minister to speak at WCSU.
      Sports: Dec 1: Women's basketball; Dec 6: Western swimmers honored by Little East Conference.